Guide to the Lower East Side Oral History Project OH.033
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Lower East Side Oral History Project
1984-1995
1991-1995
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring
Bernstein, Rachel Amelia, 1953-
Henry Street Settlement (New York, N.Y.)
Lower East Side Tenement Museum
OH.033
3 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 10 card catalog drawers
The Lower East Side Oral History Project was undertaken between 1991-1995 to document immigrant life and work on New York City's Lower East Side. Rachel Bernstein, with the New York University Program in Public History, organized collaborations with the Lower East Side Tenement Museum, Henry Street Settlement House, and the Workmen's Circle to collect interviews. Topics covered by the interviews include growing up in tenements, family life, ethnic identities, religion, paid and unpaid work, small businesses, union activity, and political activism. Interviews were conducted by NYU graduate students in Bernstein's Oral History and Public History classes. Interviews are generally accompanied by indices and the interviewer's session notes. Many have been transcribed, as well.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Lower East Side Oral History Project was undertaken between 1991-1995 to document immigrant life and work on New York City's Lower East Side. Rachel Bernstein, with the New York University Program in Public History, organized collaborations with the Lower East Side Tenement Museum, Henry Street Settlement House, and the Workmen's Circle to collect interviews.
Most of the interviews were conducted by NYU graduate students in Bernstein's Oral History and Public History classes. Additional interviews were done by volunteers from the Workmen's Circle, trained by Bernstein in two daylong seminars organized as part of a collaboration between Workmen's Circle and the Lower East Side Tenement Museum.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains interviews with immigrants and children of immigrants who lived on the Lower East Side, the majority of them from Eastern European Jewish backgrounds. Topics covered by the interviews include growing up in tenements, family life, ethnic identities, religion, paid and unpaid work, small businesses, union activity, and political activism. Interviews are generally accompanied by indices and the interviewer's session notes. Many have been transcribed, as well.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original audio media, master cassettes must be digitized before access by researchers. To request digitization of materials, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The first group of tapes were donated to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives by Rachel Bernstein in 1993. Additional tapes were deposited with the library as subsequent phases of the project were completed.
Access Restrictions
Content of majority of interviews is open for research without restrictions. Contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu for more information.
Existence and Location of Copies
Many of the interviews represented here can also be found in Series 8 of the Henry Street Settlement records (sw0058) at the University of Minnesota's Social Welfare History Archives and at the Lower East Side Tenement Museum.
Related Archival Materials
Ordinary People Extraordinary Lives Collection (OH 073)
The Henry Street Settlement records (sw0058) at the University of Minnesota's Social Welfare History Archives also contains interviews from this project. While there is significant overlap between the interviews held by each repository, both hold unique interviews, as well.
Rachel Bernstein was a professor in the Public History program at New York University. The records of this program are housed at the New York University Archives (RG 20.9).
Arrangement
Interviews are arranged alphabetically by narrator's last name in finding aid.
The master cassettes were numbered as each batch was donated to the library. As such, these materials have a roughly chronological arrangement.
Tenement houses |z New York (State) |z New York; Immigrants |z New York (State) |z New York |v Interviews; Social settlements |z New York (State) |z New York.; Jews |z New York (State) |z New York |v Interviews; Immigrants |x Housing |z New York (State) |z New York; Jews, East European |z New York (State) |z New York |v Interviews
- Karl Akiya, Oct 20, 1995; cuid154 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 128, Box 1, Box 2, Cd 1-2)
  Scope and Content Note
  Interview discusses anti-Asian prejudice and Asian movement in the Lower East Side.
  Audio fidelity greater in right channel
- Pauline Arinberg, May 21, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33H, Cassette 115)
  Historical/Biographical Note
  Pauline Arinberg spent her childhood in the Lower East Side and worked as a legal secretray in the area later in life.
- Ottile Auerbach, Oct 17, 1992 (Box 1)
  Interview discusses sickness and death in the Lower East Side
- Dolly Barkin, Jul 22, 1992 (Drawer 33D, Cassette 43, Box 1)
  Interview taken by Workmen's Circle.
- Mildred Barlow, Oct 17, 1991 (Drawer 33B, Cassette 18, Box 1)
  Interview contains discussion of Barlow's experiences at Henry Street Settlement, Vladeck House, and Good Companions Senior Center.
- Samuel Baron, Dec 13, 1991 (Drawer 33B, Cassette 19A-19B, Box 1)
  Samuel Baron was a student at Henry Street and later worked there as a teacher.
- Ana Barrera, Dec 18, 1995 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 129)
  Interview recounts experience as Central American immigrant from El Salvador.
- Bert Beck, Nov 14, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33B, Cassette 20)
  Bertram Beck became the third executive director of Henry Street Settlement in 1967. He succeeded former director Helen Hall.
- Albert Behar, May 22, 1993 (Box 1)
- Louise Behrend, Oct 17, 1991 (Drawer 33B, Cassette 21A-21B, Box 1)
  Interview discusses involvement with School for Strings and Henry Street Settlement.
- Mollie Berkowitz, Sep 2, 1993 (Drawer 33D, Cassette 45)
- Beatrice Berson, Jun 3, 1993 (Box 1, Box 2, Cd 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 46)
  Interview taken by Workmen's Circle. Discussion includes living in the Lower East Side, grandfather's grocery store, coming to America, mother as a feminist and early unionist, election day, laundry, lice, Passover Seder, learning to read and write Yiddish and Hebrew, Fourth of July, etc.
- Anne Binder, Aug 6, 1993 (Box 2, Cd 1-2, Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 47)
  Interview taken by Workmen's Circle. Includes discussion of boiling laundry, pictures of family in Russia, purchasing food on the book, first phone in 1920s, Triangle Fire, Coney Island etc.
- Bert Bloomgarden, Mar 24, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33G, Cassette 93)
  In this interview Bloomgarden recounts his father's experience as a peddler, the decline of business, and ethnic changes in LES.
- Hilda Blyn, Jun 14, 1993 (Drawer 33D, Cassette 48)
- Genya Borut, Mar 30, 1994 (Drawer 33G, Cassette 94A-94B, Box 1)
  Genya Borut was a garment worker, union activist, and young socialist in the Lower East Side.
- Aron Bram, Oct 11, 1992 (Box 1, Drawer 33A, Cassette 1)
  Aaron Bram was a concentration camp survivor.
  Interview addresses topic of child labor in the Lower East Side.
- Sam Breskin, Mar 29, 1994 (Drawer 33G, Cassette 95, Box 1)
  Sam Breskin owned the children's clothing store Rice and Breskin.
  Interview contains Breskin's memories of growing up in the Lower East Side.
- Florence Breslow, Mar 15, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33G, Cassette 96, Box 2, Cd 1-2)
  Interview conducted by Kevin Murphy. Contains discussion of parents leaving Poland, playing in tenements, parents' work, holidays, superintendent and conditions, school and first jobs, Americanization, involvement with labor Zionists, quilting business, and religious conflicts.
- Charles Bucholz, Feb 21, 1994 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 126, Box 1)
  Charles Bucholz owned Ted's Tudexo. He is the son of Polish concentration camp survivors.
- Luba Kadison Buloff, Feb 26, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33H, Cassette 106)
  Luba Kadison Buloff and her husband were Yiddish theater actors in Europe and New York City.
- John Burke, 1984 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 153, Box 1)
  John Burke was an immigrant from Ireland. He worked as a longshoreman.
- Buffy Calvert, Oct 9, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 144B, Box 1)
- Calvert/Ortiz, Oct 9, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 144A)
- Martin Canin, Nov 3, 1991 (Drawer 33B, Cassette 22A-22B, Box 1)
  Martin Canin was a piano student at Henry Street Settlement.
- Jennie Coffey, May 26, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 49)
- Beatrice Dagstine, Oct 11, 1991 (Box 2, Cd 1, Drawer 33B, Cassette 23, Box 1)
  Interview contains discussion of Vladeck House and experience as a Home Planning Workshop participant.
- Helen Davenport, Dec 1, 1995 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 127A-127B, Box 1)
  Interview discusses public housing and cooperative housing on Grand Street.
- Rose DeAngelo, November 17, 1992 (Box 1, Drawer 33A, Cassette 2A-2B)
- Albert Dehar, May 22, 1993 (Drawer 33D, Cassette 44)
- Allen Dell, Apr 10, 1994 (Drawer 33G, Cassette 97, Box 1)
  Allen Dell grew up in the Lower East Side. He was the owner of Katz's Deli.
- Shirley Deutsch, Jul 26, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 50)
- Nellie and Jim Dick, Feb 27, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33H, Cassette 112A-112B)
  Interview discusses Shelton Modern School and anarchists in the Lower East Side.
- Shirley Dornfest, Jul 30, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 51)
  Interview taken by Workmen's Circle
- Rev Norman Eddy, Oct 27, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33J, Cassette 146)
  Interview regarding the East Harlem Protestant Parish.
- Esther Eisner, May 10, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 52)
- Rebecca Epstein, Nov 15, 1992 (Box 1, Drawer 33A, Cassette 3A-3C)
  Interview addresses sickness and death in the Lower East Side.
- Helen Feldman, Apr 29, 1993 (Drawer 33D, Cassette 53, Box 1)
- Minnie Feurman, Jun 23, 1993 (Drawer 33D, Cassette 54, Box 1)
- Ida Fier, Mar 6, 1994 (Drawer 33G, Cassette 98, Box 2, Cd 1-2, Box 1)
  Interview conducted by Dawn Vandervloed. Discussion recounts childhood in the Lower East Side, immigrant parents, and orthodox upbringing. It also discusses mother's work as a janitor.
- Deborah Flynn, Oct 24, 1992 (Box 1, Box 2, Cd 1-2, Drawer 33A, Cassette 4A-4B)
  Deborah Borgenic Flynn was born in 1908. She was the dauther of clothing manufacturer Louis Borgenicht.
- Sidney Fox, Aug 25, 1993 (Drawer 33D, Cassette 55, Box 1)
- Lenora Friday, Nov 30, 1995 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 133, Box 1)
  Interview discusses education and experience as a Seward Park student.Interview discusses education and experience as a Seward Park student.
- Archie William Friedberg, Dec 17, 1992 (Box 1)
  Interview addresses the topic of child labor.
- Estelle Friedman, Jun 16, 1993 (Box 2, Cd 1, Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 56)
  Interview taken by Workmen's Circle. Includes discussion of Delancey street and Essex street, ladies' wear, entertainment, holidays, cleaning windows, theatre, a phonograph store etc.
- Mike Friedman, Oct 14, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 151A-151B)
  Interview details expereince as husband of a Central American immigrant.
- Mildred Friedman, Nov 5, 1992 (Box 1, Drawer 33A, Cassette 5A-5B)
  Interview addresses Jewish identity and the Lower East Side.
- Rose Gallo, Oct 24, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 24)
- Karla Garcia, Nov 6, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 152)
  Interview recounts experience as a Central American immigrant from Nicaragua.
- Abraham Glauberman, May 4, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 57A-57B)
- Leona Gold, Oct 21, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 25)
  Leona Gold was a Henry Street Settlement staffer and board member.
- Samuel Goldberg, Mar 31, 1994 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 124, Box 1, Box 2, Cd 1)
  Interview describes childhood in Crown Heights, ownership of Mendel Goldberg Fabrics, and union organizing issues.
- Anne Goldman, Jun 4, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33E, Cassette 58)
- Jack Goodman, May 21, 1993 (Box 1)
- Sylvia Groen, May 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 59, Box 1)
- Pearl Handman, Mar 22, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33H, Cassette 107)
  Interview discusses family's dry goods store on First Avenue and involvement in leftist politcal organization.
- Helen Harris, Apr 22, 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 60)
- David Herman, Dec 7, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 26)
  Interview talks about Henry Street Settlement.
- Francine Holtzman, Mar 30, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33I, Cassette 121A-121B)
  Francine Holtzman is a former business owner who lived and worked in the Lower East Side for over 30 years.
- Kazu Iijima, Oct 19, 1995; cuid155 (Box 1, Drawer 33J, Cassette 154, Box 2, Cd 1)
  Interview discusses anti-Asian prejudice and Asian movement.
  Audio fidelity greater in right channel, some audio bleed through present on side one of recording
- Clarence Jean, Nov 17, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33I, Cassette 132)
  Interview discusses education and experience as a Seward Park student.
- Yuri Kachiyama, Oct 6, 1995; cuid156 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 138, Box 2, Cd 1)
  Although audible, entire recording has a muted or compressed sound
- Ethel Kahn, May 14, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33E, Cassette 61)
- Nina Kalawsky, May 27, 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 62, Box 1)
- Mildred Kaminsky, Nov 9, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33I, Cassette 136A-136B)
  Interview describes experience at the Three Arrows socialist summer colony.
- Louis Kaplan, Oct 26, 1992 (Box 1)
- Richard Karp, Oct 19, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33J, Cassette 149A-149C)
  Interview talks about public housing and cooperative housing on Grand Street.
- Michael Katz, Oct 16, 1991 (Drawer 33C, Cassette 27)
  Interview regarding the history of Henry Street.
- Selma Katz, Oct 20, 1992 (Box 1, Drawer 33A, Cassette 6A-6B)
- Phillip Kiriukos, Oct 11,1991 (Drawer 33C, Cassette 28, Box 1)
- Beatrice Koblenz, Sep 6, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33E, Cassette 63)
- Yuri Kochiyama, Oct 6, 1995 (Box 1)
- Abraham Kokofsky, Jun 8, 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 64, Box 1)
- Moe Kurtman, Mar 8, 1994 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 120, Box 1)
  Interview regarding the Russian immigrant experience.
- Joel Landres, Oct 31, 1991 (Drawer 33C, Cassette 29)
  Joel Landres was a member of the Wilson Club.
- Fay Levinson, May 13, 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 65, Box 1)
  Inteview taken by Workmen's Circle.
- Gertrude Levy, Nov 11. 1992 (Box 1)
- Sadie Levy, Oct 18, 1991 (Drawer 33C, Cassette 30, Box 1)
  Interview discusses Vladeck House and Cood Companions Senior Center.
- Fannie Lipskin, Jun 26, 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 66)
- Adele Lopatin, Jul 23, 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 67, Box 1)
- Louis Mandel, May 15, 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 68, Box 1)
- Julius Manson, Dec 8, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33I, Cassette 137A-137B)
- Evelyn Markowitz, Jun 23, 1992 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 69A-69B, Box 1)
- Phoebe Thorne Marrin, Oct 15, 1991 (Drawer 33C, Cassette 31A-31B, Box 1)
  Phoebe Thorne Marrin was a board member and drama coach at Henry Street Settlement.
- Audrey McGee-Robinson, Nov 4, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 32A-32B)
  Interview recounts experience as an African-American in the Lower East Side.
- Fritzie Meyerhoffer, Oct 28, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 33A-33B)
  Fritzie Meyerhoffer's father worked as a receptionist at Henry Street for 25 years.
- Abe Miller, Jun 8, 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 70A-70B, Box 1)
- Arlene Miller, Mar 18, 1994 (Drawer 33G, Cassette 99, Box 1)
  Arlene Miller owned a clothing store in the Lower East Side.
- Mitch Miller, Oct 31, 1992 (Drawer 33H, Cassette 113A-113B)
- Carmine Morales, Feb 23, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33G, Cassette 100)
  Carmine Morales owned Classics Coffee Shop on Hester Street.
- Edward Muse, Aug 9, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33E, Cassette 71A-71B)
- Berniece Nisenson, Nov 11, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33I, Cassette 135)
- Lorraine Nussenblatt, Oct 18, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 34)
  Lorraine Nussenblatt was a client of Good Companions Senior Center.
- Nora O'Malley, Oct 16, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 35A)
  Nora O'Malley worked as a cook at Henry Street Settlement from 1933-1972.
- Esther Opalsky, Oct 27, 1992 (Box 1)
- Mercedes Ortez, Oct 22, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33J, Cassette 145)
  Interview recounts experience as a Puerto Rican immigrant.
- Charles Pasternak, May 28, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 42)
- Charles Pasternak, May 1993 (Drawer 33E, Cassette 72A-72B)
- Helen Pearl, Feb 21, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33H, Cassette 119A-119B)
  Interview describes life in the Lower East Side from 1928 to 1989.
- Fanny Platin, Dec 1, 1992 (Box 1, Drawer 33B, Cassette 16)
- Ida Radosh, Decc 1, 1992 (Drawer 33A, Cassette 7A-7B, Box 1)
  Interview discusses child labor.
- Frank Regina, May 13, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33F, Cassette 73)
- Ruth Riesner, May 20, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33F, Cassette 74)
- Candida Rios/Rosa Leon, Nov 11, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 147)
  Interview regarding East Harlem Protestant Parish
- Mike Rivera, Oct 22, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 140, Box 1)
  Interview talks about stickball in East Harlem.
- Bernard Rosen, Sep 25, 1992 (Drawer 33A, Cassette 8A-8B, Box 1)
  Bernard Rosen was born in 1934 and grew up on the Lower East Side. He married one of the granddaughters of clothing manufacturer, Louis Borgenicht.
- Marilyn Rosenblatt, Sep 29, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 36)
  Interview details experience as a piano and chorus student and dancer at Henry Street Settlement. Files also contain copies of sheet music.
- Helen Rosenfeld, May 17, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33F, Cassette 75A-75B)
- Goldie Roth, May 8, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 76)
- Augusta Rothstein, Jul 15, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33F, Cassette 77)
- Sol Rubin, May 10, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33F, Cassette 78)
- Jesus Ruiz, Nov 4, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 141, Box 1)
- Harriet Safian, Aug 3, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 79, Box 1)
- Irving Salwen, Feb 22, 1994 (Drawer 33G, Cassette 101, Box 1)
  Interview recounts childhood and experience as a business owner in the Lower East Side.
- Judith Saperstein, May 13, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 80, Box 1)
- Abdul Sarr, Nov 13, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33I, Cassette 130)
- Julius Schatsky, Nov 13, 1992 (Drawer 33A, Cassette data_value_missing_73cc51687715dfe873c087795b71b14f, Box 1)
- Sam Schatsky, Nov 23, 1992 (Drawer 33B, Cassette 10A-10B, Box 1)
- Jacqueline Schmidt, Sep 8, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 81, Box 1)
- Zelda Seltzer, May 25, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 82, Box 1)
- Norman Shapiro, Apr 17, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33G, Cassette 102)
  Interview recounts childhood in Brooklyn and experience as owner of Shapiro's Winery.
- Simon Shulman, Apr 28, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 83, Box 1)
- Celia Silverman, May 20, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 84, Box 1)
- Etta Silverman, May 31, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 85)
- Rose Singer, Nov 30, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33C, Cassette 38A-38B)
  Interview discusses memories of Vladeck House.
- Phillip Sipser, Oct 6, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33H, Cassette 114)
- Skeens/Stevens/Murray/Munoz/Diaz, Oct 1, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33J, Cassette 142)
- Clara Solomon, Dec 4, 1992 (Drawer 33H, Cassette 110)
- Clara Solomon, Apr 7, 1993 (Drawer 33H, Cassette 109)
- Sidney and Clara Solomon, Mar 16, 1993 (Drawer 33H, Cassette 111, Box 1)
- Sam Spindel, Jun 8, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 86, Box 1)
- Anne Stern, Jul 8, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 87)
  Interview talks about experience as a betting agent.
- Sally Stern, Nov 21, 1992 (Drawer 33B, Cassette 11A-11C, Box 1)
  Interview recounts memeories of the Lower East Side.
- Mollie Stiker, May 13, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 88)
- Gussie Stolzenberg, Oct 27, 1992 (Box 1, Drawer 33B, Cassette 17)
- Cissie Tamser, Nov 6, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33I, Cassette 131)
- Ruth Taube, Oct 11, 1991 (Box 1, Drawer 33D, Cassette 39A-39B)
  Ruth Taube is the director of the Home Planning Workshop at the Henry Street Settlement.
- Torres/Rentas/Mambo/Horse, Oct 22, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 143, Box 1)
- Darlene and Diedra Tremont, Nov 1995 (Drawer 33I, Cassette 134)
  Interview discusses education and experiences as Seward Park students.
- Elba Valentin, Nov 17, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 150)
- Ray Walker, Nov 6, 1995 (Drawer 33J, Cassette 139A-139B, Box 1)
  Interview discusses assimilation at Seward Park High School.
- Beverly Weinstein, Jun 3, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33F, Cassette 89A-89B)
- Jack Weiss, Feb 21, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33G, Cassette 103)
  Jack Weiss spent his childhood in the Lower East Side. His father worked as a janitor.
- Mendel Weiss, Feb 22, 1994 (Drawer 33G, Cassette 104, Box 1)
  Interview discusses the experience as a garmet worker and the rise and fall of businesses in the Lower East Side.
- Anne Weitzman, May 5, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 90)
- Lenny and Ellen Wertheim, Dec 1, 1995 (Box 1, Drawer 33J, Cassette 148A-148B)
- Farrell Williams, Apr 25, 1994 (Box 1, Drawer 33H, Cassette 105A-105B)
  Farrell Williams was a former Grand Street merchant marine.
- Aaron Wolfish, May 19, 1993 (Drawer 33F, Cassette 91)
- Natalie Zuckerman, Feb 22, 1994 (Drawer 33H, Cassette 108A-108B, Box 1)
  Interview offers commentary on shopping and fortune telling in the Lower East Side.
- Rose Zweibach, Apr 28, 1993 (Box 1, Drawer 33F, Cassette 92)
  Interview was taken by Workmen's Circle.